[Music]
with the shortest agenda, not the
shortest video in the Business Central
launch event for 2025 release wave 1. We
have the presentation of the new PowerBI
app for subscription billing. Note that
this will be not released in April, but
in 26.1. So, you have to wait an extra
month for this. But I hope if you use
subscription billing that it's get so so
much going to be worth it. Let's dive in
to PowerBI and see what we have for you.
The subscription billing module was
released in the last release wave but
got an update here in 2025 release wave
1 where we are also adding an analytical
part to it with a new PowerBI app. So
the first overview page in the app is
the subscription billing overview. As
many of the apps, we have this KPI
overview with main KPIs. Here on the top
bar, we have recurring revenue, active
customers. Um and um and then you have
different perspectives on your
subscription billing. Um what I think
you will find interesting is that for
instance yeah you have many of these
reports have drill through to details.
So the top five customer by monthly
recurring revenue you can drill through
to the customer contacts details here.
So get to the transactions. This is
something that is all over this app. And
um I think when you look at a
subscription billing there there
basically two aspects of of that that's
interesting for your the health of your
business. The first one is of course
that you need to have recurring revenue.
But the second thing also very important
for subscription businesses is churn. So
um the cost of acquiring a new
subscription customer has a certain cost
and you definitely want to make sure
that your subscriptions subscription
customers stay on and keep being um a
customer. Therefore churn is important
and we have a churn visual directly here
on the overview that shows um by month
the churn. You can also um recognize the
same kind of um picture here on the the
change in monthly recurring revenue
where the the the months where you have
a lot of uh churn typically also are the
ones where you have a a decline in re in
monthly um change of recurring revenue.
It doesn't have to be that because you
could also have months where you gain
more than you
turn. The report has a page here that
shows you the revenue year-over-year. So
you can you can see here in June we have
the current year um in and then you also
have the previous year. So this the
0.2K is what you find in uh in the June
of the previous year. So this is mainly
an interesting thing once you have at
least some data but then you can track
that year over
year. In the revenue development report
you can see both the changes uh for new
uh subscriptions but you can also see
both churn and downgrade in case you
have like different levels for for a
subscription. Uh so so this overview
here shows you all of that with the
color coding that you can see
here. But if you really want to
understand what type of churn you get
and and like why and when the churn
analysis decomposition chart is um is is
the is the key. First of all, you have
um like a change um in both downgraded
subscriptions and churned subscriptions.
You also have your churn rate KPI here,
which in this case is your monthly uh
churn rate, which
is 34%. You want to make sure that you
have this under control. Um and then you
can simply dive into the numbers with
with this either on your own. So here is
your monthly recurring revenue uh
downgrade and churn. So the the these
two together um in this visual here it's
already um distributed over change type.
But if I just u remove these I can have
an AI explain um or a statistical model
explain the key contributors to my churn
or my downgrades. It might be that you
have not a lot of variation if the data
set then you get these flat structures
but hopefully soon we'll be able to see
some variation of that. This is uh not
going well. Let's just have a look. If
not then I might want to yeah okay never
mind. Uh let me in this data set the the
AI is not really helping. So I'll just
uh do analysis myself where I go in and
check out the churn type. So let's just
get rid of the last few here and uh
simply say I would like manually uh to
understand
um the let's see the churn type change
type here and that's uh divides this
into churn and downgrade and maybe I
wanted to see that by geography maybe I
wanted to see that by customer uh and
then I can kind of understand my churn
numbers. The next three reports are very
similar. There's a return or sorry
revenue by item if you have different
items in your subscriptions. There's a
revenue by customer where you can see uh
this the revenue button but by the
customer dimension and uh the final
report here is by sales staff. So also
something where you can look at your uh
monthly recurring revenue that was sold
by different salespeople. In this uh
case, we have our old friend Jim uh Jim
Olive. And uh we can even for Jim's um
because I now know Joe is Jim's
initials. Um I can even uh if you
remember the number
962. Um I can dive into the details of
this and actually see the the
transactions behind this. These are all
the customer subscription transactions,
contract lines. And if I go down here
and check out the the revenue uh change
in revenue, it's it's 962. So that uh
that reconciles that report. The last
one last report I want to highlight in
this demo is the revenue forecast. So
instead of looking backwards on what
happened, you can use this to see what
might happen uh as a as a forecast of
the future. Note that this report does
not take churn percentages into account.
So just so you're aware of that. But uh
but now I can kind of see monthly
revenue and cost. So one of these
numbers, the blue one is the sales
forecast and the black one is our
forecast for costs. So that concludes
the demo of the new PowerBI app for
subscription billing. Remember that it's
coming in May in 26.1.
um you get a total
of let's see 14 new reports. So
hopefully this will allow you to analyze
your subscription business. And with
that I hope you have a great um great um
launch event for other sessions because
this session is over. Thank you.